[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the distance between sun and earth?",
    "option1": "149,600,000 km",
    "option2": "14,600,000 km",
    "option3": "19,600,000 km",
    "option4": "109,400,000 km",
    "answer": "149,600,000 km"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "A hypothetical reservoir for comets is called",
    "option1": "Solar flare",
    "option2": "Milky way",
    "option3": "Oort cloud",
    "option4": "Andromeda",
    "answer": "Oort cloud"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "How many satellites does Mars have?",
    "option1": 1,
    "option2": 2,
    "option3": 3,
    "option4": 4,
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Who discovered four main moons of Jupiter in 1610?",
    "option1": "Carl Sagan",
    "option2": "Galileo Galilei",
    "option3": "Johannes Kepler",
    "option4": "Nicolaus Copernicus",
    "answer": "Galileo Galilei"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "A unit of measurement used to describe the expansion of the Universe is called",
    "option1": "km/s",
    "option2": "Lemaitre value",
    "option3": "Hubble constant",
    "option4": "Pi",
    "answer": "Hubble constant"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which two gases make most of the sun?",
    "option1": "Hydrogen and Helium",
    "option2": "Hydrogen and Oxygen",
    "option3": "Oxygen and Helium",
    "option4": "Helium and Carbon",
    "answer": "Hydrogen and Helium"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which star is closest to sun",
    "option1": "Alpha Centauri A",
    "option2": "Alpha Centauri B",
    "option3": "Barnard's Star",
    "option4": "Proxima Centauri",
    "answer": "Proxima Centauri"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Vesta is which type of heavenly body?",
    "option1": "Asteroid",
    "option2": "Comet",
    "option3": "Planet",
    "option4": "Satellite",
    "answer": "Asteroid"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Largest satellite in solar system is",
    "option1": "Callisto",
    "option2": "Ganymede",
    "option3": "Moon",
    "option4": "Titan",
    "answer": "Ganymede"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "How many terrestrial planets are there in the Solar system?",
    "option1": "4",
    "option2": "3",
    "option3": "2",
    "option4": "1",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Where is the largest volcano in the Solar system?",
    "option1": "Earth",
    "option2": "Mars",
    "option3": "Jupiter",
    "option4": "Saturn",
    "answer": "Mars"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which of these stars do not make Summer Triangle?",
    "option1": "Altair",
    "option2": "Deneb",
    "option3": "Sun",
    "option4": "Vega",
    "answer": "Sun"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "A powerful Star explosion is called",
    "option1": "Big Bang",
    "option2": "Heat Blast",
    "option3": "Solar Flare",
    "option4": "Supernova",
    "answer": "Supernova"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which are the two ice giants of the solar system?",
    "option1": "Jupiter and Saturn",
    "option2": "Earth and Mars",
    "option3": "Uranus and Neptune",
    "option4": "Venus and Neptune",
    "answer": "Uranus and Neptune"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What is the orbital period of Halley’s comet?",
    "option1": "12 years",
    "option2": "32 years",
    "option3": "51 years",
    "option4": "76 years",
    "answer": "76 years"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Who speculated that our universe is expanding?",
    "option1": "Newton",
    "option2": "Hubble",
    "option3": "Galileo",
    "option4": "Copernicus",
    "answer": "Hubble"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Who had propounded the planetary laws?",
    "option1": "Newton",
    "option2": "Hubble",
    "option3": "Galileo",
    "option4": "Kepler",
    "answer": "Kepler"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Who had proved first that our earth and another planet are revolving?",
    "option1": "Aristotle",
    "option2": "Galileo",
    "option3": "Copernicus",
    "option4": "Hubble",
    "answer": "Copernicus"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Which one of the following elements occurs most abundantly in our universe?",
    "option1": "Hydrogen",
    "option2": "Helium",
    "option3": "Oxygen",
    "option4": "Nitrogen",
    "answer": "Hydrogen"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "The stellar and solar source of energy is:",
    "option1": "Nuclear fusion",
    "option2": "Nuclear fission",
    "option3": "Electromagnetic induction",
    "option4": "Electromotive force",
    "answer": "Nuclear fusion"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "The device employed to measure the diameters of stars and our galaxy (Milky Way) is called:",
    "option1": "Photometer",
    "option2": "Barometer",
    "option3": "Viscometer",
    "option4": "Interferometer",
    "answer": "Interferometer"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which planet has most satellites?",
    "option1": "Jupiter",
    "option2": "Saturn",
    "option3": "Uranus",
    "option4": "Neptune",
    "answer": "Saturn"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Which one of the following planet is also called morning star or evening star?",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Venus",
    "option3": "Earth",
    "option4": "Mars",
    "answer": "Venus"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The planet which completes one revolution in 88 days around the Sun is:",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Venus",
    "option3": "Earth",
    "option4": "Mars",
    "answer": "Mercury"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "The planet whose density is less than water and on keeping in the water it will start to float:",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Earth",
    "option3": "Mars",
    "option4": "Saturn",
    "answer": "Saturn"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "The planet Neptune was discovered by:",
    "option1": "Galley",
    "option2": "Galileo",
    "option3": "Kepler",
    "option4": "Newton",
    "answer": "Galley"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "The small groups of planetary pieces which are confined and revolving between Mars and Jupiter are called:",
    "option1": "Asteroids",
    "option2": "Celestial bodies",
    "option3": "Comet",
    "option4": "Meteors",
    "answer": "Asteroids"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "The day on which the Sun’s direct rays cross the celestial equator is called:",
    "option1": "ecliptic",
    "option2": "equinox",
    "option3": "solstice",
    "option4": "aphelion",
    "answer": "equinox"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Who invented the telescope?",
    "option1": "Lippershey",
    "option2": "Galileo",
    "option3": "Hypatia",
    "option4": "Kepler",
    "answer": "Lippershey"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "What is the visible part of the Sun called?",
    "option1": "stratosphere",
    "option2": "photosphere",
    "option3": "lithosphere",
    "option4": "atmosphere",
    "answer": "photosphere"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "What makes a planet a dwarf planet?",
    "option1": "size and shape",
    "option2": "distance from sun",
    "option3": "color",
    "option4": "smell",
    "answer": "size and shape"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "How many times larger is the radius of the Sun than that of the Earth?",
    "option1": 109,
    "option2": 10,
    "option3": 4.8,
    "option4": 1025,
    "answer": 109
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Approximately how many miles are there in a light-year?",
    "option1": "0.59 million",
    "option2": "5.9 billion",
    "option3": "5.9 trillion",
    "option4": "5.9 million",
    "answer": "5.9 trillion"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Who first discovered Saturn’s rings?",
    "option1": "Galley",
    "option2": "Galileo",
    "option3": "Kepler",
    "option4": "Newton",
    "answer": "Galileo"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "What was the first animal launched into orbit?",
    "option1": "Chimpanzee",
    "option2": "Guinea Pig",
    "option3": "Cat",
    "option4": "Dog",
    "answer": "Dog"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "Who was the first man in space?",
    "option1": "Alexey Leonov",
    "option2": "Neil Armstrong",
    "option3": "Scott Carpenter",
    "option4": "Yuri Gagarin",
    "answer": "Yuri Gagarin"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Who was the first woman in space?",
    "option1": "Sally Ride",
    "option2": "Mae Jemison",
    "option3": "Valentina Tereshkova",
    "option4": "Svetlana Savitskaya",
    "answer": "Valentina Tereshkova"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "What was Buzz Aldrin’s first name at birth?",
    "option1": "Stephen",
    "option2": "Scott",
    "option3": "Earl",
    "option4": "Edwin",
    "answer": "Edwin"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Who was the second U.S. astronaut to travel into space?",
    "option1": "John Young",
    "option2": "Edward White",
    "option3": "Roger Chaffee",
    "option4": "Virgil Grissom",
    "answer": "Virgil Grissom"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "The first American astronaut to float in space",
    "option1": "John Young",
    "option2": "Edward White",
    "option3": "Roger Chaffee",
    "option4": "Virgil Grissom",
    "answer": "Edward White"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "India's first scientific satellite",
    "option1": "Aryabhatta",
    "option2": "Bikramaditya",
    "option3": "Chandrakanta",
    "option4": "Devashree",
    "answer": "Aryabhatta"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "The first space tourist in the world",
    "option1": "Anousheh Ansari",
    "option2": "Charles Simonyi",
    "option3": "Dennis Tito",
    "option4": "Mark Shuttleworth",
    "answer": "Dennis Tito"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "Which of the following phenomena cannot be observed on the surface of the Moon?",
    "option1": "Rising and setting of the Sun",
    "option2": "Solar eclipse",
    "option3": "Motion of comets",
    "option4": "Twinkling of stars",
    "answer": "Twinkling of stars"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Which of the following planets has a revolution time which is shorter than its rotation time?",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Venus",
    "option3": "Mars",
    "option4": "Jupiter",
    "answer": "Venus"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Which planet looks reddish in the night sky?",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Venus",
    "option3": "Mars",
    "option4": "Jupiter",
    "answer": "Mars"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Which female astronaut spent the maximum time in space?",
    "option1": "Lisa Norwak",
    "option2": "Kalpana Chawla",
    "option3": "Sunita Williams",
    "option4": "Valentina Tereshkova",
    "answer": "Sunita Williams"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "Which planet has the fastest revolution time?",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Venus",
    "option3": "Mars",
    "option4": "Jupiter",
    "answer": "Mercury"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "An astronaut in outer space will observe sky as",
    "option1": "Red",
    "option2": "Blue",
    "option3": "Black",
    "option4": "White",
    "answer": "Black"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "Which of the following planets rotates in a direction opposite to the direction of earth's rotation?",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Venus",
    "option3": "Mars",
    "option4": "Jupiter",
    "answer": "Venus"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "Which of the following planets has a lesser rotation time than the Earth?",
    "option1": "Mercury",
    "option2": "Venus",
    "option3": "Mars",
    "option4": "Jupiter",
    "answer": "Jupiter"
  }
]